CHOIR:
♪ The Simpsons ♪
(tires screeching)
D'oh!
(screams)
(tires screeching)
You know,
we should visit
Shelbyville
more often.
They have a store
that just sells shoes.
I feel like
I'm in Paris!
LISA: Oh! The famous Shelbyville
Theater District!
Can we see a play?
Play?!
All plays suck,
all the time,
and always will,
and everyone knows it!
Look, we'll compromise.
We'll go see a play...
that Lisa
doesn't want to see.
Muh...
Let's see...
there's Equus
starring Sideshow Mel,
the Three Dollar Bills
in Gay, Gay, Gay!
Ooh!
Song of Shelbyville.
(up-tempo music playing)
♪ From the schoolhouse
where our grandparents learnt ♪
♪ To the bad zoo
where all the animals burnt ♪
♪ We're home to Christian,
Muslim and Jew ♪
♪ Although not many
of the last two. ♪
(music changes)
♪ There's a girl
for every guy ♪
♪ Birthplace
of the button fly ♪
♪ In good ol' Shel-bee-ville! ♪
Say, fellow Shelbyvillian,
enjoying our famous
low humidity?
I'll say.
The only thing lower
than our humidity
are the greens fees
on our public golf course.
Which one?
All three!
Yes. Yes.
Why look,
it's Springfield Billy!
(hooting)
What are you doing
here in Shelbyville?
I came here for
the legalized gambling.
But Springfield Billy,
we don't have
legalized gambling here.
Sure you do.
I saw a bumper sticker
that said "Free Tibet."
(laughter)
(gasps): They're saying
Springfielders are stupid hicks.
It's like lookin'
in a mirror.
What's a mirror?
It's a big city word
for reversifyin' glass.
Oh.
(laughs): That show
was hilarious.
That Springfield Billy
cracks me up.
For your information,
Springfielders can be
intelligent and articulate.
I happen to know because
we're from Springfield.
Springfielders?! Oh.
(hooting)
MARGE: This is
the worst crisis
the Springfield Cultural
Activities Board has ever faced.
Those Shelbyvillians
are maligning us all.
I've never heard such
mean-spirited hate-hoots.
We've got to upgrade
Springfield's image,
show them we're more
than just a town
that's still afraid
of eclipses.
Hey, how 'bout we open
a fancy restaurant,
and when people check their hats
and coats, we steal 'em?
Why do you come
to these meetings?
Free water.
There must
be something else.
Think, Marge, think.
Culture...
Vulture...
Birds of prey...
Pray in a church...
The Father,
Son and Holy Ghost...
Ghosts are scary...
Scary rhymes with Gehry!
That's it!
Architect Frank Gehry!
He could build us
a concert hall
like he did in Los Angeles.
Well, we could
use a new HQ
for the Springfield
Philharmonic.
They're playing Gustav Mahler
in abject squalor.
(orchestra playing)
Little help?
Next time we're keeping it.
Then it's agreed.
We ask Frank Gehry
to build us a concert hall.
Bill, bill,
Bilbao bill...
Snoopy stationery!
MARGE'S VOICE:
Dear Mr. Gehry,
would you please build
a concert hall for our town?
We may not be the biggest city,
or the prettiest,
but we were
the first city in America
to abandon the metric system.
(Marge chuckling)
(groans)
(gasps)
Frank Gehry,
you're a genius!
Behold the new
Springfield Concert Hall.
(audience oohs)
And none of this
would have happened
if not for a letter I received
from one little girl.
I wrote that letter.
You wrote I was "the bestest
architect in the world"?
Well, aren't you?
All in favor of building
a $30 million "screw you"
to Shelbyville?
ALL: Aye!
Get off my masterpiece,
you punks!
I'll call your mothers!
Yo, Frank Gehry!
Like curvi-linear forms much?
(groans)
(humming)
(purring)
Hey cat, get
your own pants!
(grunting)
Kids!
Why's the cat so fat?
Dad, Snowball's
not fat.
She's just
got winter fur.
(grunting)
Okay, she's fat.
(groans)
Can't breathe...
Someone dangle
some string.
(meows halfheartedly)
I'm so excited.
It's like giving birth
to a child of steel and iron.
(Beethoven's
"Fifth Symphony" begins)
(German accent):
Where is everybody going?
The symphony,
she has just started!
So? We already heard
the "dum dum dum dum."
The rest
is just filler.
I thought
this was gonna be
the soundtrack
to the movie Beethoven.
Was I sadly mistaken.
It sounds better
on my cell phone.
("Fifth Symphony"
ringtone plays)
Don't leave now!
The next piece is an atonal
medley by Philip Glass.
(panicked screaming)
(wind blowing)
QUIMBY: You stupid hicks!
Why didn't you tell me
you hated classical music?
We didn't have time.
The concert hall
was designed
and built so quickly.
We're broke,
but I have a plan.
We change the name of the town
to escape our creditors.
I need names, people!
Lima, Peru!
Gotham City!
Wiggumville!
Burger King!
BURNS: Perhaps I can be
of assistance.
Smithers, tear me
a new drape hole.
If you hand over
the concert hall to me,
I'll assume the debt and all
of your problems will disappear.
The building is yours.
Excellent!
MARGE (gasps):
He's turned it into a prison!
(groans)
(hooting)
MAN: Let's see now.
Barely finished
high school.
You've challenged me
to fight six times
since the interview began...
Make it seven!
(grunts)
Mr. Simpson,
I like the way
you go nuts
over nothing.
Now all you have to do
is pass this drug test.
Hmm.
(humming)
Hmm?
("In-A-Gadda-Da-Vida" plays)
Cool, but I'll never
pass with this.
I better
switch samples.
(laughs)
(humming)
BURNS: Simpson, I haven't
seen so many drugs in a wang
since I ran
a Chinese opium den!
"Crack, smack, uppers,
downers, outters, inners,
horse tranquilizers,
cow paralyzers, blue bombers,
green goofers,
yellow submarines,
LSD Mach 3,
and trace amounts of...
(grousing)
human urine?"
Well, there must have
been a mistake.
My body is a temple.
Guards, remove this coked-out
man-balloon from my sight!
But he misread my pee!
He misread my pee!
(sobbing)
We're not
overfeeding her.
We've been
giving her
this low-fat
cat food!
I'll bet she's sneaking food
from someplace else.
Let's follow her!
I'd rather
follow the dog.
I think he's up
to something.
(engine whirring)
One thing
at a time, Bart.
(yowling)
(meowing)
There you are, Smokey!
(purring)
BART: Snowball II
has another family!
This is worse
than when we thought
Mom was having
an affair.
Turned out
she was just going
to the library
to cry.
Now she just bottles up
her misery like a normal mom.
BURNS: Gentlemen,
my prison
is losing money.
We need more convicts
in the dungeonarium.
Dungeonarium.
That's catchy.
Uh, well, I could
beef up arrests
by enforcing some
of these old forgotten laws.
(grunts)
Okeydokey.
Let's see here.
Uh, here's one from 1834.
"It's unlawful for a man
to be hatless
during daylight hours."
Hmm.
Ha, ha, Smithers.
If I didn't arrest you
that night in the park,
I'm not going
to arrest you now.
Stupid prison guard jobs
thinks it's so big.
(grunts)
Everyone gets
a prison job but me.
(grunts)
All my best friends
are guards.
(grunts)
They think they're
so cruel and corrupt,
but they're not.
Okay, boys, here's
a loony law from 1911.
"Five kicks of the same can
shall be considered
illegally
transporting litter."
(grunts)
(grunting)
That's a hard five.
-(siren blaring)
-All units move in.
We're puttin' you away,
Kicky Mantle.
And give that can
the whole CSI treatment.
You know, lab tests,
weird lights,
shots from the can's
point of view.
(chuckling):
Yeah, that's it.
Lots of flash
and no meaning.
(crickets chirping)
-(blubbering)
-(laughs):
Okay, new meat,
you're clean.
(groans)
I'm not supposed
to be new meat.
I'm supposed
to have your job.
I'm sick of you positing
an alternate reality!
(loud groaning)
(metal clinking)
No Frank Gehry-designed prison
can hold me!
Ha, ha!
(groaning)
Ho. Whoa.
(grunts)
Oh, my God,
that man might be hurt!
Guards, there's
a prisoner in there!
(tires squealing)
Nice nab, Simpson.
You did the right thing
squealin' on that guy.
Squealin'? No.
I was just wanted
to help him.
Mm, whatever.
How'd you like
to be a full-time rat?
Really?
You mean eat cheese,
gnaw through electrical cords,
things like that?
(gnawing)
Not exactly.
Mr. Burns,
I've thought about it,
and I don't want
to be a snitch.
It's not an honorable life.
Now, now,
there are perks.
A private cell,
extra dessert,
and this adorable
little hat.
Well, I am a sucker
for a little hat.
So, we have
an agreement?
Well... I don't know.
But it's the only way
you'll survive in here.
Well, I would like
to survive long enough
to see the effects
of global warming.
I've got an inside tip
that it's all a bunch of crap.
Okay, you've found
your snitch.
Excellent!
Now, what have
you got for me?
(loud whisper): Homer Simpson
has become a snitch.
(groans): Tell me something
I don't know.
(loud whisper):
Sometimes
I go to movies alone.
Say, is that
a gang tattoo?
I thought those
weren't allowed.
Yeah, it's a gang
I was in as a kid.
G.M.S.:
Galactic Mystery Solvers.
Ah, the only mystery we couldn't
solve was how not to grow up.
Hmm.
That's right--
an unauthorized tattoo.
I came here
right away.
Very good.
Here you go!
42-inch plasma TV
as a thank you
from your, uh...
Your, uh, mother.
Oh, that "my mother."
Tell him thanks.
Okay, Tattoo Man.
It's a month
in the hole for you.
Solitary confinement?
But without my weekly
canasta, I'll die.
It's-it's
my raison d'etre.
(sniffs) Ew.
Smokey, you've got
that awful smell on you again.
Hey!
That's the smell
of her real family!
The Simpsons!
And for your information,
our walls have a bunch
of dead raccoons in them,
but we are saving up
the money to find them.
Well, whatever.
Smokey's our cat.
(meows)
Smokey, stay!
Now back.
Heel.
Snowball does tricks?
Sure. C'mon, Smokey,
do your Smokey shuffle.
(kids clapping)
Well, I don't care
what you say.
She still loves us more.
Don't you, Snowball?
(hisses, snarls)
(purring)
You toyed with my heart
like it was a toy heart.
(wheels squeaking)
Gentlemen, we must determine
which of our fellow
inmates has become
the Rodentus
Incarcerarium.
You heard the boss.
Find the rat.
I found the rat,
and he's right here.
I ain't the rat;
I'm the pigeon.
I thought you
was the mole.
No, you're thinking of that
guy who was the canary.
But we can all agree,
we work in a business
with a very rich lexicon.
Rich lexicon,
very rich.
(murmuring in agreement)
Ooh, a Tiffany's box!
And the thing inside
is from Tiffany's!
Homie, you've never
done this before.
How'd you afford it?
Well, if you
really must know, uh,
I'm a prison snitch.
(gasps)
Haven't you seen
what happens to people
who rat in prison movies?
Sure, they're on top
of the world.
Then there's
a big riot scene.
Then... I don't know.
I usually doze off.
The prison snitch is killed!
And that could be you.
Because you're
the prison snitch!
(all gasp)
(growling)
What are you
dopes looking at?
You've never seen
bling-bling before?
What is it they have
that keeps Snowball
coming back
to their house?
Only one way
to find out.
My baby turtle crawled
into your basement window.
Oh, you poor boy.
What's
your turtle's name?
Uh...
Apron Boobs-face?
Really?
Well, let's go find it.
And what's your name?
Uh...
Shoes... Butt-back?
HOMER: Uh-huh.
Hmm.
Psst.
There's a jailbreak
tonight.
How come nobody
told me before?
I sent you an e-vite.
You never responded.
Nice netiquette, jerk.
There's gonna be
a breakout tonight.
Very good.
Now, I'd like a little
more information.
Are biographies arranged
by author or subject?
What is Bart still
doing in there?
You forgot to take
some brownies.
Thanks, Mother Dexter!
I'll be back tomorrow.
Bart, why were you
in there so long?
Lis, that place is great!
They have a jukebox
in the basement.
And look at the trick
they taught me!
(humming a circus tune)
Are you watching?
(groans)
When they come busting out,
we'll be ready.
Every single guard
is outside waiting for them.
Something don't
feel right.
Usually when
there's a jailbreak,
there's electricity
in the air,
like the calm
before a summer storm.
Or, uh, right before
a heavyweight fight.
Mine's more poetic.
(grunts)
Now, where the hell are they?
PRISONERS (chanting):
Kill the rat!
What happened
to the guards?!
PRISONERS: Kill the rat!
Okay, okay. Don't panic.
Maybe they'll tire themselves
out with their chant.
Kill the rat!
(screams)
I call the balls
of his feet!
(all clamoring)
Marge, they're gonna kill me!
Oh, eh...
I only did what I had
to do to survive...
in a style befitting
a French monarch.
(screams)
Fly, Segway, fly!
(yelling)
(screaming)
(screaming fades)
We've all heard
of a laugh riot,
but a prison riot?
Kent Brockman high above
Montgomery Burns
State Penitentiary,
where our expensive
Thermocam 3000 is finally
being used for something.
This red glow is the heat
from a pack of inmates
who are desperately looking for
prison snitch, Homer Simpson--
this massive blob over here--
who is attempting to hide
in the kitchen area.
Good luck, blobby.
PRISONERS: Kill the rat!
Then have snack!
Homer.
Homer, where are you?
(grunts)
Marge!
How did you get in here?
As president
of the cultural board,
I was given a key
to the concert hall.
There's the filthy rat
we're gonna kill.
And his wife, who sometimes
drives my son home from school.
Oh, you must be
Michael's dad!
Marge, c'mon!
We'll be safe
in the gas chamber.
Go!
I want you to look into
the faces of those poor men.
Each one is a life you made
worse with your ratting.
(all grunting)
Oh, Marge,
I'm sorry I got you
into this mess.
Can I snitch on my heart
and say I love you?
Oh, Homie...
(both moaning)
(all coughing)
Tear gas, my one weakness.
(groaning)
You can come in, governor.
Well, I'll make these rioters
regret their folly.
This prison will make Abu Ghraib
look like the Four Seasons.
Smithers, we'll
need electrical wire, a hood
and someone who can really
point at genitalia.
Done and done, sir.
Mmm?
Hold on a minute.
Governor, I've been using
my powers of snitching for evil,
but now I want
to tattle for good.
This prison
is a hellhole.
They feed us
horse meat,
with traces
of jockey meat!
I'll have you know I buy
the finest cuts of beef.
(bugle playing)
The guards
are sadistic and cruel.
I can't help
the way I am.
When I was a boy,
I saw my father murdered
before my eyes.
By me.
Governor, I think
the only fair solution
is to pardon all
these thugs and murderers.
Well, since there's no room
in the prisons you came from,
I'm releasing you all
to a garbage barge,
where you will
bare-knuckle-box
till one of you emerges
as king of your floating hell.
(cheering)
You know what I missed
in the joint?
Just lying here watching you
sleeping sweetly.
Sleeping sweetly.
Sleeping sweetly...
I won't tell
if you don't tell.
Listen to me!
This whole building is unsafe.
They cut corners everywhere.
People! It's a deathtrap.
No, Dad,
you fell asleep
in front of the TV,
watching
The Towering Inferno.
How do you know the title
of my prophetic vision?
Shh!
Captioned by VISUAL DATA
Enhanced by Fotokem