♪ The Simpsons ♪
-(chalk screeches)
-(bell rings)
(work whistle blows)
-(sucking)
-(register beeping)
(jazzy solo)
(tires screech)
D'oh!
-Aah!
-(tires screech)
ANNOUNCER (on TV):
Live, from Mount Splashmore,
the tri-county area's funnest
water recreation facility,
it's "The Krusty
the Clown Show."
-Hey, kids!
-(cheering)
You know, today's the last day
of our special week
on location at fabulous
Mount Splashmore.
And I just want to say
the people here
have been super to me
and Sideshow Mel.
-(horn squeaks)
-The food, the grog...
Oh, they threw us
a brunch yesterday
with fresh fruit and
the most delicious melon.
Oh, we ate till we plotzed. And of course,
the thing I'm gonna miss most
is those special, special
Mount Splashmore water slides.
God bless 'em. So much fun,
so many memories. Excuse me a minute.
-It has been a great week, hasn't it Lise?
-(sighs)
I hope all you kids come out this weekend
and really pack this place
just to show 'em
how grateful I am.
I told them you would.
Don't make me a liar. (laughs)
Okay, kids it's time to...
Yeah!
-(crowd cheering)
-(Krusty laughing)
This is a rather
shameless promotion.
-Hey, it worked on me.
-Me too.
(snoring)
-Will you take us to Mount Splashmore?
-No.
-No!
-Will you take us to Mount Splashmore?
-No.
-No!
-Will you take us to Mount Splashmore?
-No.
-(screams) No! No!
-Will you take us to Mount Splashmore?
-No! No!
If I take you, will you two
shut up and quit bugging me?
-Yeah.
-Of course.
-Well?
-Will you take us to Mount Splashmore?
-(screaming) Yes!
-BOTH: Thanks, Dad.
(horn blares)
Come on, Homer,
get the lead out!
(horn honking)
-(groaning)
-(honking continues)
Oh, gee...
Homer, that suit doesn't leave
much to the imagination.
(inhales deeply, groans)
-(horn blares)
-Heads up, kids. I'm moving the seat back.
It is back.
(tires squeal)
(screaming)
All right, everybody
stick together.
We don't want to get separ--
D'oh!
MAN (on speaker):
Challenge the raging waters of death.
Dare to discover
what water is really made of:
H2whoa!
-Whoa.
All right! No line.
BART:
Ay, caramba.
Okay, Lise, turn on
the waterworks, babe.
Mommy!
-I want my Mommy!
-BART: Step aside, come on.
Spread out, spread out.
Lost kid comin' through.
Look out, fatso.
Coming through, coming through.
Pardon me. Moving to
the front of the line.
-(wailing)
-Hey, Lise, nice work, babe.
No, Maggie, stay
in the shallow end.
To hell with this.
Slide inspector coming through.
Please move to the right.
Grab the handrail, young man.
Out of my way!
I'm here for your safety.
God bless that man.
(crowd grumbling)
(screams)
Bitchin'!
(laughing)
(thud)
Hey! What?
Come on, you stupid tube.
(alarm buzzing)
Hmm, looks
like there's a jam in Delta Sector.
Hmm. Well, it's too
big to be human.
Well, send down a few kids.
That should dislodge it.
MAN (on radio):
Keep 'em coming, Biff.
Roger.
(kids laughing)
(kids screaming happily)
(Homer screaming)
(kids screaming in terror)
(thudding)
HOMER: D'oh!
Can't... breathe.
-Too many... children.
-(thudding continues)
(scattered boos)
Eyewitnesses estimate
the man's weight
at somewhere between
400 and 500 pounds.
And now on the lighter side
of the news,
-and I use the term loosely. (chuckles)
-D'oh!
-(reporters shouting)
-No, the slide is perfectly safe.
-This was an isolated incident.
-I understand that, Krusty.
But, Krusty, isn't that
exactly what you said
right before the recall of tainted
Krusty brand mayonnaise?
Now, Kent you know that
question is out of bounds.
This interview's over.
All right, family.
I want the truth.
Don't pull any punches.
Am I just a little bit
overweight?
-Well, am I?
-Forgive us, Dad,
but it takes time to properly
sugarcoat a response.
Ohh!
Oh, 437! What?
Fifty-five?
Oh, my God!
Three hundred and...
What's this-- 150?
Ah! Oh. Ah! Oh.
Oh, my God!
It's 260 pounds!
I'm a big fat pig!
Now, Homer,
you do have big bones.
Marge, no one gains
30 pounds of bone.
(breathing heavily)
I'm going on a diet.
From this day forward,
I pledge there will be
no pork chop too succulent,
no doughnut too tasty,
no pizza too laden
with delicious topping,
to prevent me from reaching
my scientifically determined
ideal weight.
As God is my witness,
I'll always be hungry again!
(stomach gurgling)
D'oh! Shut up!
This old attic's kind of
spooky, isn't it, boy?
I said, isn't it, boy?
-(switch clicks)
-Ahh!
(stammers)
Don't ever do
that to me again.
-Okay.
-D'oh! Bart!
(cries out)
Get away from that thing
and help me find
my athletic equipment.
-(mouse squeaks)
-Hmm.
Hey, Homer,
I found your weights.
Oh, the glutemus maximizer.
Hey! Who's the mop top
with the big schnozz?
Don't you know anything, boy?
That's Ringo Starr.
What is this?
Hey, your mother
must have painted this.
I guess she thought
he was kinda cute.
What? Hey!
What the--
Marge!
No, Homer.
Don't be jealous.
I was a schoolgirl.
The Beatles were very popular,
and I had a crush on them.
Likely story.
Oh, why did I have
to start my diet
on pork chop night?
Now Homer,
we've got steamed vegetables
and rice cakes for you.
(shudders)
Well, wait a minute.
Well, hey, I've been setting
my drinks on these things.
Well, they're only
35 calories apiece.
Hello? Hello?
Hello, taste?
Where are you?
You can put a little
something on top for flavor.
Hey, hey,
now you're talking.
Hey, Mom!
These paintings are good.
While I know firsthand
how fragile young talent is,
I'd love to hear the particulars
of how your gift was squashed.
(groans)
Well...
(scoffs)
No, not another portrait
of that bongo-beating
Liverpudlian.
But Mr. Schindler, I--
Someone might have
used this canvas
to create a masterpiece.
Instead, you've
soiled it forever.
-Now, this is art.
-Thank you, Mr. Schindler.
LISA: Oh, Mom, I can't
believe you gave up painting
because of one
small-minded art teacher.
MARGE: I was so upset,
I decided to send the portrait
to the only man on Earth whose
opinion I could really trust.
LISA:
And what was Ringo's response?
Mmm, I never got any,
and I never painted again.
Maybe you could take a class
at Springfield Community College.
I think it's
a very nice idea.
-Don't you, Homer?
-Do I have to do anything?
-No.
-Great! Fine!
-Go nuts! Hee-hee-hee.
-(timer dings)
-Mmm! Only 35 calories.
-(groans)
Oh, hello, Mrs. Homer.
Apu, what are you
doing here?
I've just enrolled in
the screenwriting class.
I yearn to tell the story
of an idealistic young Hindu
pushed too far
by convenience store bandits.
I call it
"Hands Off My Jerky, Turkey."
-Clever title.
-Oh, thank you.
Actually my brother
Sanjay thought of it.
-Next up.
-My mother would like to enroll
in "Painting From Life" 2-B,
please.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Not so fast there, pint-size.
I'm afraid no one can enroll
until Professor Lombardo
personally inspects and
approves their portfolio.
-Lisa, this was a bad idea.
-Mom!
Ah, very good.
Fabulous!
Ah, even better.
You have real talent.
Hmm. Do you
really think so?
My high school
art teacher hated them.
What? The man was a fool.
But still, one must admire
the force of his conviction.
-Then I'm in the class?
-Oh, my dear,
there couldn't be a class
without you.
Now, if you'll excuse me,
nature calls.
Marvelous!
(straining)
Stupid weights.
The heavy hands don't work
unless you move, Homer.
I can't move, boy.
Oh, really?
(grunting)
Oh!
Now, using the Lombardo method,
you learn to see
everyday objects
as a simple grouping
of geometrical shapes.
Here, we see how
two concentric circles
various trapezoids, ellipsis--
and yes, even a rhombus--
can create an adorable
little bunny rabbit.
It's just that easy!
(groaning)
(straining)
♪ Lincoln, Lincoln,
I've been thinkin' ♪
♪ What the hell
have you been drinkin'? ♪
♪ Is it water, is it wine? ♪
♪ Oh, my gosh,
it's turpentine ♪
-(both cheering)
-Go! Go! Go!
♪♪
(cat screeching)
Bravo!
Walk away from it.
Now it belongs to the ages.
You. Not another stroke.
Oh, well, maybe one more.
That's it! Perfect!
Mmm... indeed.
Marge, you find
the inner beauty
of your subject
and bring it out for all to see.
Well, thank you,
Professor Lombardo.
Well, you're welcome,
my dear.
-(quietly) Marge, walk with me.
-(Marge groans)
Marge, they've asked me
to submit the best painting
from my class
to the Springfield
Art Exhibition next week.
I've decided to choose
your Bald Adonis.
Really?
You're so supportive.
I wish every teacher
was like you.
Marge, please, I don't take
praise very well!
Oh! Another triumph!
Hmm.
Yeah.
-I can't believe it!
-(applause)
-Yeah!
-Go Mom!
-All right!
-Whoo-hoo!
I'm a work of art!
"Last Supper,"
eat your heart out.
-(kissing)
-(camera shutters clicking)
Garbage!
What matchbook art school
did you flunk out of?
You ham-fisted
nearsighted house painter!
Smithers,
throw this on the dung heap.
I'm sorry.
This isn't working out. I quit.
-Well, Smithers,
-(door slams)
I guess that's what you call
your artistic temperament.
Sir, I must remind you
that the dedication
of the Burns Wing of the museum
is only six days away.
Damnation, Smithers.
This idea of yours to immortalize me
in a portrait
was as half-baked
as your idea about
me having children.
Smithers, find me an artist.
Sir, I'm afraid you've
systematically alienated
Springfield's entire
art community.
The only one left is
this Mrs. Homer Simpson.
-Who?
-Well, she won first prize
in the Springfield Art Fair,
and is the wife of an employee.
-She'll be easily intimidated.
-Excellent.
Once again,
the wheel has turned,
and dame fortune
has hugged Montgomery Burns
to her sweet,
perfumed bosom.
Somebody up there
likes me, Smithers.
SMITHERS: Somebody down here
likes you too, sir.
BURNS: Shut up!
♪♪ (Western showdown music)
D'oh! Whoo!
D'oh! Whoo-hoo!
Whoo-hoo!
249! Yeah! Wa! Wa! Wa!
Marge! Marge!
Look at me.
My clothes are just
hanging off me.
That's wonderful,
isn't it, kids?
Pass the moo juice.
Kids, remember what I told you
about showing a little support?
-Way to go, Dad!
-You look mah-velous.
Oh, what a family.
Hey, what gives?
These doughnuts are piling up.
Huh. Yeah, Homer Simpson
went on a diet.
Oh, my God,
and I just bought a boat.
(straining)
(tap)
Well, don't people answer
the door these days?
Allow me, sir.
Open up! Open up!
Mr. Burns. Oh, would
you like to come in?
Mr. Burns would like to commission you
to do a portrait of him.
Have you ever painted
the rich and powerful?
Well, no. Just Ringo Starr.
Ring-go?
He was the drummer
for a rock and roll combo
called The Beatles, sir.
Beatles, eh? Oh, yes.
I seem to remember
their off-key caterwauling
on the old Sullivan show.
What was Ed thinking?
Mrs. Simpson,
this commission
and all of its glory
can be yours
but first you must look me
straight in the eye
and answer one
simple question.
-Okay, shoot.
-Can you make me beautiful?
Hmm. Well, I don't think
that will be a problem.
I'm no matinee idol,
you know.
Well, maybe not,
but I have the gift
of being able
to see inner beauty.
Hmm. Mrs. Simpson,
you may immortalize me.
Ah, sir,
at last the world will
see you as I always have.
Yes, yes, yes. Now, don't be stingy
with the blush, Smithers.
There. There.
Now, you-- paint!
(groaning)
Honey, I'm home.
Oh, there's an
original sentiment.
(screams)
Take it outside, Simpson.
I'm male modeling.
I'm painting
his portrait, Homer.
(laughing)
Isn't that wonderful?
My work and my home life
come together
in such a nice way.
Marge, may I see you
in the other room?
Honey, he's nuts.
He thinks he's handsome.
Please, you've got
to make him look handsome.
Please, please, please,
please, please, please, please.
Now, Homer, don't worry.
All I need to do is find
Mr. Burns' inner beauty.
Ohh! Okay.
Hmm. What were you like
as a boy, Mr. Burns?
Did you have a dog
that you loved?
Well...
(cries out)
There's something on my leg!
Get it off! Get it off!
-Mr. Burns, she's just a baby.
-BURNS: Ugh!
All right, all right.
Who took the funny pages?
So Ziggy goes
to the repair shop,
and there's a sign
on the doorbell reading
-"Out of order."
-(chuckles)
Ah, Ziggy, will you ever win?
(humming tune)
-Oh, my!
-If you'll excuse me,
I'm changing
for a board meeting.
I'm so sorry, Mr. Burns.
Hey, Mom, did he have
those spots all over his body?
-I heard that.
-Oops.
Would you feel more comfortable
if I left, too, sir?
Of course not, Smithers.
You're... you're like a doctor.
(kettle whistling)
BURNS: Smithers,
I want my tea!
Doesn't it bother you that
he orders you around like that?
(chuckles) Actually, I value
every second we're together
from the moment I squeeze
his orange juice in the morning
till I tuck him in at night.
He's not just my boss.
He's my best friend, too.
Bah! Too hot!
You're right, sir.
It's scalding me
as we speak.
(gasps, grumbles)
Dear Sally.
In response to your letter
of December 12, 1966,
me favorite color is blue,
and me real first name
is Richard.
-(bell dings)
-Thanks for the snapshot.
-You're a real cute bird. Love, Ringo.
-(bell dinging)
P.S. Forgive the lateness
of my reply.
-Mr. Starr, tea and crumpets.
-Just set it over there.
Sir, if you'll forgive an old
Brit his impertinence,
your devotion to your fans
is nothing short of remarkable.
Well, Weatherby, they took
the time to write me,
and I don't care
if it takes me another 20 years.
I'm going to answer
every one of them.
Hello. What's this?
From Springfield, U.S.A.
Gear.
♪♪
Will you cease
that infernal tootling?
-I was just practicing.
-(groans)
Mr. Burns, it's hard to
discover your inner beauty
while you're shouting
at an eight-year-old girl.
We've only got two days left,
so I'd advise you to shut up and paint!
(groans)
All right scale,
you don't like me
and I don't like you,
but I've been very good,
so you'd better treat me right.
All right! Whoa-ho-ho!
Whoo! Whoo!
Marge, I'm 239
and I'm feeling fine.
Look, I'm using the original
notches that came with my belt.
That's wonderful, Homer.
I'm so proud of--
Let me get this straight.
You're pleased
with your current appearance?
(laughs)
Why, my good man,
you're the fattest thing
I've ever seen
-and I've been on safari.
-(chuckling)
(crying) If you need me,
I'll be in the refrigerator.
-(sobbing)
-(groaning)
Mr. Burns, I've had enough
of your posing.
I can finish
the portrait myself.
Thank goodness. Another day
in this suburban nightmare,
and I would have needed
half a white Valium.
Thank you for your
gracious hospitality.
See you at the unveiling.
(whistling)
(gasps) Homer, what are you doing?
Give me that!
No, Burns is right.
What's the use?
Don't you listen to him.
He's just a mean, little S.O.B.
Oh, Marge.
I thought there was
some good in everybody
-until I met him.
-Yeah, well,
just as long as you paint
a nice picture of him by noon tomorrow.
-I don't think I can.
-What?
Marge, you have to!
I can't make that man
beautiful!
I'm just not good enough.
I guess I'm no artist.
Hmm. Hello. What's this?
It's for you, Marge,
from merry old England.
"From the desk
of Ringo Starr."
RINGO:
"Dear Marge.
"Thanks for the fab painting
of yours truly.
"I hung it on me wall.
"You're quite an artist.
"In answer to your question--
"Yes, we do have hamburgers
and fries in England,
"but we call french fries
'chips.'
"Love, Ringo.
P.S. Forgive the lateness
of my reply."
-Ooh!
-Come on, Marge, paint.
I think you can do it.
Okay, Homer,
if you think I can.
RINGO: ♪ Got to pay your dues if
you want to sing the blues ♪
♪ And you know
it don't come easy ♪
♪ You don't have to shout
or leap about ♪
♪ You can even play
them easy ♪
(chamber music playing)
(playing "For He's
a Jolly Good Fellow")
Friends, art lovers,
security personnel,
today is a red letter day
for the Springfield Palace
of Fine Arts.
A new wing for our museum,
ooh, and a portrait
commemorating the man
who ponied up the dough.
Ladies and gentlemen,
may I invite you
to behold Montgomery Burns.
(straining)
Smithers.
-(crowd gasps)
-(glass shatters)
-Oh.
-D'oh!
I don't care for this at all.
Um... hello.
My name is Marge Simpson,
and I painted this.
Maybe you'd like to know
what possessed me to do it.
Well, I guess I wanted to show
that beneath Mr. Burns'
fearsome head
with its cruel lips,
spiteful tongue
and evil brain,
there was a frail,
withered body,
perhaps not long
for this world,
as vulnerable and beautiful
as any of God's creatures.
-(applause)
-Hmm?
-MAN: Yes! Oh!
-(whistling)
Provocative but, uh, powerful.
He's bad, but he'll die.
So I like it.
Hmm...
Marge, a word, please.
You know, I'm no art critic
but I know what I hate,
and I don't hate this.
Your painting is bold
but beautiful
and, incidentally,
thanks for not making fun
of my genitalia.
I thought I did.
♪♪
Shh!
CAPTIONS ENHANCED BY
ROUNDABOUT ENTERTAINMENT INC.